

Experienced Data Science professional with 5+ years of Diverse Experience, actively looking for a job across the industry with the desired skill set of Data Science, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Deep Learning and Python.



Current Designation: Lead Data Scientist Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 4 Month(s)

Current Company: HCL Technologies Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Noida Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Machine Learning, Data Science, Python, MySQL, Pytorch, TensorFlow, Deep Learning, NLP, Tesseract, Text Mining, Clustering, Predictive Modeling, Data Modeling, Data Visualization, Text Analytics, matplotlib, Computer Science, Data

Management, Predictive Maintenance

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 21-Jan-21 Last Active: 21-Jan-21

# **Summary**

A 5+ years experienced Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer, with B TECH. in Computer Science. I have been deeply passionate and enthusiastic about the field of Machine Learning, Data Science, Deep Learning, Neural Networks, Predictive modeling, and Artificial Intelligence. I have practical experience in creating ML & DL Models using various libraries like Sci-kit Learn, Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras, pandas, BERT, embeddings etc and along with the skills to do the data analysis using Matplotlib, Seaborn etc. I also possess a theoretical as well as practical understanding of a broad range of machine learning algorithms such as Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Support Vector Machines, Decision Trees, PCA etc.

## Work Experience

**HCL Technologies** as Lead Data Scientist

Aug 2018 to Till Date

Working as a Data Scientist and creating ML & DL model. Also deploying them in Test Environment.

Genpact Headstrong Capital Markets as Machine Learning Engineer Dec 2016 to Aug 2018

Sopra Steria as Software Engineer in Python Sep 2015 to Dec 2016

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Uttar Pradesh Technical University (UPTU) in 2015

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Python	3+	2020	5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
MySQL, Mongo DB		2020	
Linux, Windows			
SVN, GIT			
TensorFlow	2+	2020	2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
NLTK, Sciki-learn, Pandas			5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
DOCKER		2020	1 Year(s)
Machine learning, Deep learning			5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Neural net		2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Word vectors, Glove, Clustering		2020	2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
Decision Tree, Linear Regression		2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
BERT, RNN, LSTM, Word2Vec		2020	2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
KNN, K-Means, SVM, MNB		2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Logistic regression, Random Forest		2020	3 Year(s)

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

#### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

# **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time